<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-26T09:57:09+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Magicblock</title><subtitle>The Framework for on-chain games on Solana/SVM</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The MagicBlock Quest Is Here: Where the Magic Begins</title><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/quest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The MagicBlock Quest Is Here: Where the Magic Begins" /><published>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/quest</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.magicblock.gg/quest/"><![CDATA[<p>Today, we’re launching the first MagicBlock Quest: a multi-part experience that will begin in the MagicBlock community and evolve onchain, giving you new ways to explore and interact with the MagicBlock world.</p>

<p>We built MagicBlock to power real-time experiences that stay entirely within Solana — where your assets, tokens, and actions remain in one place without being split across chains or slowed down by bridges. No interruptions, no fragmentation, no extra steps. A fast, simple way to use the full power of Solana without needing to leave it behind.</p>

<p>Whether you are playing a game, placing a trade, or interacting with a smart contract, everything happens in real time, with instant transactions and no lag. You get the speed and responsiveness you expect from everyday apps combined with the transparency, control, and freedom that only decentralized systems can offer.</p>

<p>This MagicBlock Quest is your invitation to see that vision in action. You will engage across different spaces, from community channels and creative challenges to live products and partner protocols. Whether you are contributing socially, creatively, or onchain, every step gives you a better sense of what MagicBlock enables and where it is going.</p>

<h2 id="what-to-expect">What to Expect</h2>

<p><strong>Phase 1: Social Sync</strong> The first phase is off-chain. You will dive into challenges that immerse you in the MagicBlock world, from sharing insights to decoding lore to engaging with educational content and other community members.</p>

<p>These early social quests are more than a starting point. They will also feed into future progression, acting as a booster for later stages of the quest. The more you participate now, the more value your future quests will earn as things evolve.</p>

<p><strong>Phase 2: Onchain Unlocks</strong> In the second phase, things go onchain. You’ll interact with the world of MagicBlock through real-time transactions, product experiences, and partner integrations — FlashTrade, ZeeBit, and SuperSize among them. These onchain actions help model the future of real-time gaming and finance.</p>

<p>The more you engage, the more you unlock.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-join">How to Join</h2>

<p>We’re opening up the first phase on the 15th of April. To join the quest:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Follow us on [<a href="https://twitter.com/magicblock">Twitter</a>/<a href="https://discord.com/invite/MBkdC3gxcv">Discord</a>/etc].</li>
  <li>Watch for the first challenge drop on Galxe.</li>
  <li>Participate, share, and signal back.</li>
</ol>

<p>More info and lore will unlock as the community moves through it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Magicblock</name></author><category term="Announcement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we’re launching the first MagicBlock Quest: a multi-part experience that will begin in the MagicBlock community and evolve onchain, giving you new ways to explore and interact with the MagicBlock world.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/quest.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/quest.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">dTelecom x MagicBlock: Powering the Future of Real-Time Decentralized Communication</title><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/dtelecom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="dTelecom x MagicBlock: Powering the Future of Real-Time Decentralized Communication" /><published>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/dtelecom</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.magicblock.gg/dtelecom/"><![CDATA[<p>At MagicBlock, we’re building a real-time engine for decentralized applications on Solana. Our cutting-edge ephemeral rollup technology delivers low latency, ultra-cheap fees with dedicated blockspace and, and elastic scalability, all while preserving composability with Solana’s ecosystem. Today, we’re excited to announce our partnership with <a href="https://www.dtelecom.org/">dTelecom</a> — a perfect use case for our technology that demonstrates its real-world impact.</p>

<h2 id="a-perfect-match-real-time-performance-meets-decentralized-communication">A Perfect Match: Real-Time Performance Meets Decentralized Communication</h2>

<p>dTelecom is creating a fully decentralized alternative to services like LiveKit and Agora, where anyone can become a bandwidth provider in a permissionless network. Their platform requires exactly what MagicBlock excels at delivering:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Sub-50ms latency</strong> essential for VPN and real-time communication</li>
  <li><strong>Seamless Solana integration</strong> without liquidity fragmentation</li>
  <li><strong>Ultra-cheap fees</strong> thanks to dedicated blockspace and transactions batching</li>
  <li><strong>Dynamic scaling</strong> to handle unpredictable global usage patterns</li>
  <li><strong>Gas abstraction</strong> for frictionless user experiences</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>“We founded dTelecom with a simple but powerful vision: communication infrastructure should be as open, resilient, and accessible as the internet itself,” says Vadim Filimonov, Co-founder at dTelecom. “Finding the right technical partner was crucial to delivering on this promise. MagicBlock’s unique approach to scaling Solana makes them not just a vendor, but a foundational pillar of our infrastructure strategy.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="why-this-partnership-matters">Why This Partnership Matters</h2>

<p>Building real-time, low-latency applications on the blockchain has historically forced difficult trade-offs between performance and decentralization. With MagicBlock’s technology, dTelecom can deliver:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>A Web2-level, seamless experience</strong> with truly private, censorship-resistant communication.</li>
  <li><strong>A sustainable economic model</strong> for node operators through instant, on-demand ephemeral rollups</li>
  <li><strong>Intuitive developer tools</strong> that don’t sacrifice user experience</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>“This is a really exciting case where Ephemeral Rollups can help the unit economics of an ambitious network like dTelecom, aside from pure performance,” says Andrea Fortugno, Co-founder at MagicBlock. “Their vision for decentralized communication aligns perfectly with our capabilities, and we’re proud to provide the technology that helps make their ambitious roadmap possible.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="reimagining-communications-infrastructure">Reimagining Communications Infrastructure</h2>

<p>dTelecom’s vision goes beyond just another communication tool — they’re building the foundation for truly censorship-resistant, private internet access through a comprehensive suite of tools including dVPN and real-time communication SDKs.</p>

<p>For their diverse ecosystem of bandwidth providers, privacy-conscious users, and developers, MagicBlock provides the invisible but essential infrastructure layer that ensures their platform can compete with centralized alternatives on performance while maintaining all the benefits of decentralization.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“We evaluated numerous scaling solutions, but only MagicBlock offered what we truly needed—real performance without sacrificing the principles that matter to us,” continues Filimonov. “Their technology isn’t just complementary to our vision; it’s essential to delivering what we’ve promised our users and developers.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h2>

<p>As dTelecom expands its SDKs, node operator program, and enterprise integrations, MagicBlock will scale alongside them—providing the performance foundation that makes true decentralized communication possible.</p>

<p>This partnership opens a new chapter for both teams and the wider Solana ecosystem, demonstrating that with the right infrastructure, decentralized applications can truly compete with—and exceed—their centralized counterparts.</p>

<p>Real-time. Reliable. Unstoppable. This is the future of communication we’re building together.</p>

<p><strong>Follow dTelecom at <a href="https://x.com/DTEL_org">https://x.com/DTEL_org</a></strong></p>

<p><strong>Unleash the Power of MagicBlock</strong>. Explore our <a href="https://docs.magicblock.gg/introduction">documentation</a>, or follow us on <a href="https://x.com/magicblock">X</a> and <a href="https://discord.com/invite/MBkdC3gxcv">Discord</a> to stay in the loop. Let’s build the future — faster, smarter, together.</p>]]></content><author><name>Magicblock</name></author><category term="Announcement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At MagicBlock, we’re building a real-time engine for decentralized applications on Solana. Our cutting-edge ephemeral rollup technology delivers low latency, ultra-cheap fees with dedicated blockspace and, and elastic scalability, all while preserving composability with Solana’s ecosystem. Today, we’re excited to announce our partnership with dTelecom — a perfect use case for our technology that demonstrates its real-world impact.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/dtelecom.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/dtelecom.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing the Verifiable Randomness Solana Plugin</title><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/solana-plugin-vrf/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing the Verifiable Randomness Solana Plugin" /><published>2025-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/solana-plugin-vrf</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.magicblock.gg/solana-plugin-vrf/"><![CDATA[<p>In blockchain applications, getting truly random numbers is surprisingly difficult. Whether building games, raffles, or fair selection mechanisms, you need randomness that everyone can trust—something traditional coding approaches can’t provide.</p>

<p>Today, we’re unveiling our solution: <strong>The Verifiable Randomness Function (VRF), a Solana Plugin</strong>. This new capability is available to all developers building on Solana, with even greater performance and speed when combined with MagicBlock’s Ephemeral Rollups.</p>

<p>This update is the next feature announced in our rollout of <strong>Solana Plugins</strong>, which extends Solana’s capabilities with powerful new functions while maintaining full composability with the ecosystem.</p>

<h2 id="why-is-true-randomness-so-hard-in-blockchain">Why Is True Randomness So Hard in Blockchain?</h2>

<p>Generating true randomness in blockchain environments faces several key challenges:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Everything must be predictable</strong>: Blockchains need all validators to reach the same conclusion, but randomness is unpredictable by nature.</li>
  <li><strong>Trust issues</strong>: The system isn’t fair if anyone can predict or influence “random” numbers.</li>
  <li><strong>Proving fairness</strong>: Users need to know that random selections weren’t manipulated.</li>
  <li><strong>Speed matters</strong>: External solutions are often slow and break the seamless user experience.</li>
</ul>

<p>Most existing solutions force developers to compromise on one or more of these requirements.</p>

<h2 id="the-verifiable-randomness-solana-plugin-simple-but-powerful">The Verifiable Randomness Solana Plugin: Simple but Powerful</h2>

<p>The Verifiable Randomness Solana Plugin solves these challenges with an elegant approach:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Your application requests a random number</li>
  <li>A network of independent oracles collaborates to generate the randomness</li>
  <li>Mathematical proofs verify that the result is truly random and unmanipulated</li>
  <li>The verified random value becomes available in your application</li>
</ol>

<p>The process happens quickly and directly within MagicBlock’s infrastructure, without external services or complex integrations.</p>

<h2 id="vrf--ephemeral-rollups-a-performance-breakthrough">VRF + Ephemeral Rollups: A Performance Breakthrough</h2>

<p>While the Verifiable Randomness Plugin works well on standard Solana, it truly shines when combined with MagicBlock’s Ephemeral Rollups. Here’s why:</p>

<p><strong>Physical proximity advantage = low latency</strong>: When VRF oracles are co-located with your Ephemeral Rollup, the physical distance that data needs to travel is dramatically reduced. Instead of requests and responses traveling across the internet to external oracle networks, they move within the same infrastructure—reducing latency from seconds to milliseconds.</p>

<p><strong>Architectural efficiency = lower gas fees</strong>: Our integrated approach requires just a single transaction. This reduces gas costs and complexity, making randomness more affordable and straightforward to implement in your applications.</p>

<p><strong>Customizable environment = faster block times</strong>: Ephemeral Rollups allow you to configure faster block times and dedicated compute resources tailored to your application. This means you can process randomness requests in an environment optimized for your specific needs rather than competing with other traffic on the base chain.</p>

<p>For applications where randomness is a critical component—like real-time games or high-frequency mechanisms—these performance advantages become a game-changer, enabling experiences that wouldn’t be possible with traditional approaches.</p>

<h2 id="real-world-applications">Real-World Applications</h2>

<p>Here are some ideas of what becomes possible with the Verifiable Randomness Solana Plugin:</p>

<p><strong>For Games &amp; NFTs</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Fair loot drops and rewards</li>
  <li>Random game elements and encounters</li>
  <li>NFT trait generation during minting</li>
  <li>Fair winner selection for competitions</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>For DeFi &amp; Governance</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Random validator or committee selection</li>
  <li>Fair distribution of limited opportunities</li>
  <li>Lottery and raffle mechanisms</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="getting-started-is-easy">Getting Started is Easy</h2>

<p>Ready to add verifiable randomness to your Solana application? The process is simple:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Build your application using MagicBlock’s Ephemeral Rollups</li>
  <li>Enable the Verifiable Randomness Solana Plugin</li>
  <li>Use our straightforward SDK to request and use random values</li>
</ol>

<p>Our <a href="https://github.com/magicblock-labs/Ephemeral-VRF">GitHub repository</a> provides comprehensive documentation and examples for developers who want to explore technical details.</p>

<h2 id="beyond-randomness-the-future-of-solana-plugins">Beyond Randomness: The Future of Solana Plugins</h2>

<p>The Verifiable Randomness Solana Plugin is just the beginning of what’s possible with our plugin architecture. We’ve already launched additional plugins that enhance what developers can build on Solana:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Pricing Oracle Plugin</strong>: Get real-time, low-latency price feeds directly in your applications</li>
  <li><strong>AI Oracle Plugin</strong>: Integrate AI capabilities into your on-chain logic without external dependencies</li>
</ul>

<p>Each Solana Plugin addresses a key capability gap in the ecosystem, providing developers with powerful tools that simplify building advanced applications.</p>

<h2 id="start-building-with-solana-plugins-today">Start Building with Solana Plugins Today</h2>

<p>By using Solana Plugins powered by MagicBlock’s Ephemeral Rollups, developers can focus on freely building innovative experiences without worrying about complex infrastructure challenges.</p>

<p>Verifiable randomness is a foundational building block for the next generation of decentralized applications, and now, it’s natively available on Solana through our plugin system.</p>

<p>Ready to explore randomness for your application? Check out our <a href="http://github.com/magicblock-labs/ephemeral-vrf">GitHub repository</a> for everything you need to get started including technical documentation, implementation examples.</p>

<p>Stay tuned as we continue expanding the Solana Plugins ecosystem with more powerful capabilities in the months ahead!</p>]]></content><author><name>Magicblock</name></author><category term="Announcement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In blockchain applications, getting truly random numbers is surprisingly difficult. Whether building games, raffles, or fair selection mechanisms, you need randomness that everyone can trust—something traditional coding approaches can’t provide.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/vrf.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/vrf.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">From Hackathon Winner to Fully On-Chain Pioneer – How Lewis Built Supersize</title><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/supersize-hackathon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Hackathon Winner to Fully On-Chain Pioneer – How Lewis Built Supersize" /><published>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/supersize-hackathon</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.magicblock.gg/supersize-hackathon/"><![CDATA[<p>For many builders, hackathons are more than just competitions—they can be a launchpad for ideas to turn into real, successful projects.</p>

<p>Case in point: Lewis Arnsten, co-founder of <a href="https://supersize.gg/">Supersize</a>, a fully on-chain, real-money casual game that is powered by MagicBlock to create fast, seamless multiplayer experiences.</p>

<p>Before <a href="https://blog.colosseum.org/announcing-the-winners-of-the-solana-radar-hackathon/">winning the Gaming Track at Colosseum</a>, Lewis had a rough prototype and a vision. A few weeks later, he had validation, momentum, and early users testing his game.</p>

<p>If you’re considering joining a hackathon, Lewis’ story is proof that it’s worth taking the leap.</p>

<p>Also…In case you missed it, we have just announced the <a href="https://realtime.magicblock.app/">Real-Time Hackathon</a>, here to bring your big idea to life.</p>

<h2 id="from-idea-to-winning-a-hackathon">From Idea to Winning a Hackathon</h2>

<p>Lewis’ journey into fully on-chain gaming wasn’t a straight path. He had been experimenting with on-chain mechanics for a while, frustrated by the limitations of centralized servers in multiplayer games.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“I thought it would be cool to make <a href="https://agar.io/">Agar.io</a> where you could just wager money, and when you ate, you could eat free money and take people’s money. I thought it was a cool idea.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>But turning that cool idea into a real, scalable game required a foundation that could support real-time transactions and trustless wagering. Lewis explored different blockchain solutions before settling on Solana and MagicBlock’s ephemeral rollups, which provided the low latency and composability he needed.
By the time Colosseum rolled around, Lewis had an MVP running on Devnet but needed a space to test, refine, and prove the concept.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“I had an MVP but hadn’t launched on mainnet yet. It was just on devnet… I think I got it onto mainnet right around the time the hackathon ended, and I had a bunch of early users running tests.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Colosseum gave him the structure to focus, the pressure to ship, and the right audience to validate his idea.</p>

<h2 id="the-hackathon-winning-formula-what-made-supersize-stand-out">The Hackathon Winning Formula: What Made Supersize Stand Out?</h2>

<p>Winning a hackathon isn’t just about building something cool—it’s about presenting a technically sound, clearly differentiated project with long-term potential.</p>

<h2 id="for-supersize-the-key-factors-were">For Supersize, the key factors were:</h2>
<ul>
  <li>✅ <strong>A working prototype</strong> – Even though it wasn’t perfect, it was live, interactive, and showed the core mechanics.</li>
  <li>✅ <strong>Clear innovation</strong> – It wasn’t just a game; it was one of Solana’s first fully on-chain, real-money multiplayer games.</li>
  <li>✅ <strong>Strong storytelling</strong> – Lewis backed his technical execution with a <a href="https://www.chaincatcher.com/en/article/2146119">clear thesis</a> on why fully on-chain gaming mattered and how it could scale.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>“We won the gaming track… I think it was a mix of proving our engineering capability, having a real-time fully on-chain game that worked, and having a clear thesis on how we wanted to monetize these casual games.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="lewis-tips-for-hackathon-success">Lewis’ Tips for Hackathon Success</h2>

<p>Having been through multiple hackathons, Lewis has a few key takeaways for anyone thinking about joining one:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Start Before the Hackathon
    <blockquote>
      <p>“I knew what I wanted to build before it started… I already had the foundations, so I could focus on refining it rather than starting from scratch.”
While many people start their projects during the hackathon, having an idea and some early progress can give you an edge. Even if you don’t have working code, thinking through your concept beforehand helps you move faster once the competition begins.</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
  <li>Have a Prototype People Can Use
    <blockquote>
      <p>“When the judges came to test it, everything worked, and it was the first real-time fully on-chain game. That helped a lot.”
A working prototype is 10x more compelling than just an idea. Even if your project is rough, buggy, or incomplete, showing that it works in some form goes a long way.</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
  <li>Tell a Compelling Story
    <blockquote>
      <p>“A lot of teams were building fully autonomous worlds, but we had a different approach. We showed why casual, real-money games make sense on-chain.”</p>
    </blockquote>

    <p>Judges and potential supporters aren’t just looking at the tech—they want to see the why behind your project. What problem are you solving? Why does your approach matter? How could it scale beyond the hackathon?</p>
  </li>
  <li>Use Hackathons to Build Relationships
    <blockquote>
      <p>“I found my co-founder after the hackathon, and that’s been huge.”</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Winning is great, but one of the biggest benefits of hackathons is the network you build. Whether it’s meeting potential co-founders, getting feedback from experienced builders, or connecting with investors, hackathons can open doors far beyond the competition itself.</p>

<h2 id="thinking-about-joining-a-hackathon-heres-why-you-should">Thinking About Joining a Hackathon? Here’s Why You Should</h2>

<p>If you’ve been thinking about building something, a hackathon is one of the best ways to test your idea, push yourself to ship, and get honest feedback.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“I feel like I was kind of lucky because I started early and knew exactly what I wanted to build… but the biggest thing was just putting it out there and seeing how people responded.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Hackathons aren’t just about prizes. They’re about validation, momentum, and opportunities.</p>

<p>If you want an opportunity to bring your game idea to life, check out MagicBlock’s Real-Time Hackathon.
The gaming track is designed to help builders explore real-time multiplayer mechanics, low-latency transactions, and fully on-chain game economies.</p>

<p>It’s also the perfect lead-up to Colosseum—giving you a chance to test ideas, refine your project, and enter Solana’s biggest hackathon with a head start.</p>

<p>👉 <a href="https://form.typeform.com/to/xHzLT587">Sign up for MagicBlock’s Real-Time Hackathon here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Magicblock</name></author><category term="Announcement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For many builders, hackathons are more than just competitions—they can be a launchpad for ideas to turn into real, successful projects.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/supersize-hackathon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/supersize-hackathon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">MagicBlock x Pyth Lazer: Real-time DeFi can now compete with CeFi</title><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/pythlazer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MagicBlock x Pyth Lazer: Real-time DeFi can now compete with CeFi" /><published>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/pythlazer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.magicblock.gg/pythlazer/"><![CDATA[<p>Today, we’re excited to announce a strategic partnership between MagicBlock and Pyth to bring 1ms price feeds to all Solana dApps. By combining MagicBlock’s high-performance network infrastructure with Pyth Lazer’s financial data feeds, we are unlocking new possibilities for institutional-grade DeFi applications that demand speed, accuracy, and deep liquidity.</p>

<p>At MagicBlock, our mission is to empower developers with the fastest, most scalable execution environments in Web3. Pyth Lazer’s high-fidelity, real-time data feeds provide an essential component for DeFi applications, ensuring that traders and protocols have access to the best available market data without relying on centralized sources.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“MagicBlock’s ephemeral rollups enable us to deliver the lowest-latency, high-performance trading experiences, while Pyth Lazer ensures that our partners have the most accurate real-time data. Together, we’re eliminating the barriers to high-performance DeFi and we are paving the way for institutional-grade products.” – Andrea Fortugno, Co-Founder of MagicBlock</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="revolutionizing-on-chain-finance">Revolutionizing On-Chain Finance</h2>

<p>Latency and unreliable data sources are two of the biggest challenges facing decentralized finance. DeFi protocols require execution speeds comparable to traditional finance while maintaining transparency and security. By integrating with Pyth Lazer, MagicBlock delivers:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Real-Time Price Data</strong>: 1ms price feed and Ephemeral Node colocation ensure that financial data remains as granular as possible</li>
  <li><strong>Seamless Composability</strong>: Builders can integrate Pyth Lazer’s data feeds into MagicBlock-powered applications without additional bridges or intermediaries.</li>
  <li><strong>Scalability for Institutional Use</strong>: MagicBlock’s elastic transaction processing enables scalable DeFi applications to support institutional-grade trading volumes.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="a-shared-vision-for-the-future-of-defi">A Shared Vision for the Future of DeFi</h2>

<p>MagicBlock and Pyth share a vision of a decentralized financial ecosystem that rivals the speed and reliability of traditional markets. With this partnership, we’re equipping builders with:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Reliable, decentralized financial data</strong> for trading apps, spot and derivatives protocols.</li>
  <li><strong>Optimized transaction execution</strong> that scales dynamically to meet network demand.</li>
  <li><strong>Security, verifiability and transparency</strong> of fully onchain apps built on Solana</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Pyth Lazer’s integration with MagicBlock represents a breakthrough for DeFi infrastructure. By combining Pyth Lazer’s millisecond-latency price feeds with MagicBlock’s ultra-fast execution environment, Solana developers have the tools to build apps that match the performance of traditional markets and have the potential to create the next generation of finance.” – Abhimanyu Bansal, Head of BD at Douro Labs</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This collaboration is a call to DeFi builders everywhere: the future of finance is real-time, data-driven, and unstoppable. With MagicBlock and Pyth, the next generation of decentralized financial applications is here.</p>

<h2 id="unleash-the-power-of-magicblock--pyth-lazer">Unleash the Power of MagicBlock &amp; Pyth Lazer</h2>

<p>Join us in shaping the future of high-performance DeFi. Explore our documentation.</p>

<p>Explore our <a href="https://docs.magicblock.gg/introduction">documentation</a>, or follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/magicblock">Twitter (X)</a>, <a href="https://discord.com/invite/MBkdC3gxcv">Discord</a> to stay in the loop. Let’s build the future — faster, smarter, together.</p>]]></content><author><name>Magicblock</name></author><category term="Announcement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we’re excited to announce a strategic partnership between MagicBlock and Pyth to bring 1ms price feeds to all Solana dApps. By combining MagicBlock’s high-performance network infrastructure with Pyth Lazer’s financial data feeds, we are unlocking new possibilities for institutional-grade DeFi applications that demand speed, accuracy, and deep liquidity.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/pythlazer.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/pythlazer.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">MagicBlock x Jito: Enhancing Security for Realtime Decentralized Applications on Solana</title><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/jito/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MagicBlock x Jito: Enhancing Security for Realtime Decentralized Applications on Solana" /><published>2025-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/jito</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.magicblock.gg/jito/"><![CDATA[<p>Today, we’re thrilled to announce our partnership with <a href="https://www.jito.network/">Jito Network</a> to integrate their restaking solution, strengthening the security of realtime, decentralized applications on Solana.</p>

<p>MagicBlock is a realtime network extension that enables developers to build performant fully onchain applications, from FOC games to high-frequency DEXes that can rival centralized trading venues.</p>

<p>Developers can now implement the entire logic of their apps on Solana and execute computations - that would traditionally run on centralized servers— in a specialized, temporary environment called an “Ephemeral Rollup,”. developers can achieve the <strong>same performance of traditional servers while avoiding single points of failure</strong>. This allows for <strong>persistent, composable, and verifiable applications</strong> that operate at the speed and scale needed for realtime, decentralized applications.</p>

<p>By integrating Jito (Re)staking and slashing, MagicBlock is adding an important layer of economic incentives that accelerate decentralization and enhances the security of the network.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Our goal at MagicBlock has always been to supercharge Solana’s capabilities while avoiding the fragmentations of L2s. Ephemeral Rollups give developers superpowers and additional optionality to build and scale Real-time apps on Solana, and this partnership with Jito allows us to secure and decentralize the network even further.”– Andrea Fortugno, Co-Founder of MagicBlock</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="unlocking-better-economic-incentives-for-solana-builders">Unlocking Better Economic Incentives for Solana Builders</h2>

<p>Jito’s restaking infrastructure is designed to enable staked assets to secure multiple networks or services, thereby increasing their security and contributing to the overall robustness of these systems.
Through this partnership, MagicBlock developers can now benefit from:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Enhanced Security</strong>: Restaking allows staked assets to secure Ephemeral Validators, who are kept accountable for their stake and must behave correctly to avoid getting slashed.</li>
  <li><strong>Increased Economic Utility</strong>: By participating in restaking, users and tokenholders can unlock additional value from their assets, leading to an extra layer of economic incentives.</li>
  <li><strong>Seamless Integration</strong>: The restaking framework integrates with existing developer workflows without added complexity, allowing for flexible, secure and scalable ER sessions that can easily manage staked assets.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>“We’re excited about exploring Solana scaling solutions and the types of use cases they unlock for application developers,” says Hayden Tsutsui (business development, (re)staking). “By integrating Jito (Re)Staking, the main benefit of this partnership is two-fold: (1) MagicBlock’s engine and ephemeral rollups will remain tethered to the base layer, and (2) Jito Network and its set of node operators will continue to push the boundaries of providing a secure foundation for use cases beyond the L1.”</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="a-shared-vision-for-performance--decentralization">A Shared Vision for Performance &amp; Decentralization</h2>

<p>We believe that <strong>Web3 should match the performance of Web2, without sacrificing decentralization</strong>.</p>

<p>This collaboration isn’t just about enhancing security—it’s about empowering developers with superpowers, allowing them to build secure, realtime applications directly on Solana while avoiding the fragmentations of L2s and single-point-of-failures of web2 infrastructure.</p>

<p>Over the coming months, we’ll explore in detail the different modules related to the network security, including releasing staking and restaking functionalities—stay tuned.</p>]]></content><author><name>Magicblock</name></author><category term="Announcement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we’re thrilled to announce our partnership with Jito Network to integrate their restaking solution, strengthening the security of realtime, decentralized applications on Solana.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/jito.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/jito.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">MagicBlock x Flash Trade: Accelerating the Future of High-Performance DeFi</title><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/flashtrade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MagicBlock x Flash Trade: Accelerating the Future of High-Performance DeFi" /><published>2025-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/flashtrade</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.magicblock.gg/flashtrade/"><![CDATA[<p>Today, we’re thrilled to announce a transformative partnership with <a href="https://www.flash.trade/">Flash Trade</a>, Solana’s leading asset-backed perpetuals exchange. Together, we’re setting a new standard for DeFi, delivering lightning-fast trading experiences that redefine the boundaries of speed and composability.
At MagicBlock, we empower builders to create without compromise—enabling performance that rivals traditional finance while embracing the trustless, decentralized ethos of Web3. By joining forces with Flash Trade, we’re unlocking the potential for a Binance-like exchange built entirely on Solana!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“MagicBlock’s cutting-edge network infrastructure gives us the power to deliver on our vision: a CEXY trading experience that matches the speed of Web2 exchanges while staying true to the decentralized principles we believe in.” – <a href="https://x.com/allinbitcoin_">Anas</a>, Co-Founder of Flash Trade.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>MagicBlock Ephemeral Rollups technology empowers Flash Trade to deliver:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Real-Time UX</strong>: Sub-50ms latency for a trading experience that feels as intuitive as any Web2 platform.</li>
  <li><strong>Unfragmented Liquidity</strong>: Keep users entirely within the Solana ecosystem—avoiding bridges and maintaining the full potential of composability.</li>
  <li><strong>Dynamic Scalability</strong>: Elastic transactions per second (TPS) to handle even the most extreme demand without missing a beat.</li>
</ul>

<p>With MagicBlock’s real-time network powering Flash Trade, high-frequency traders and institutional players alike can experience decentralized trading that meets the performance and expectations of centralized solutions.</p>

<h2 id="shared-ambition-limitless-potential">Shared Ambition, Limitless Potential</h2>

<p>Together with the team at Flash Trade, we share a bold vision: <strong>to make decentralized finance as fast as centralized exchanges</strong>. By overcoming fragmentations and scalability challenges, we’re enabling builders to dream bigger and achieve more.
With our real-time network, dynamic co-location, and cutting-edge runtime extensions, MagicBlock ensures that DeFi developers can build experiences that are as reliable as they are groundbreaking.</p>

<h2 id="equipping-builders-for-whats-next">Equipping Builders for What’s Next</h2>

<p>At MagicBlock, we’re not just solving for speed; we’re sparking possibility. Our ephemeral roll-up technology ensures developers have the tools they need to scale, innovate, and deliver with confidence.</p>

<p><strong>What this means for builders</strong>:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Unwavering Reliability</strong>: Consistent performance, no matter the network conditions.</li>
  <li><strong>Enhanced Ecosystem Connectivity</strong>: Seamless composability with Solana’s liquidity-rich environment.</li>
  <li><strong>Freedom to Innovate</strong>: Remove the technical roadblocks holding you back—build boldly, experiment fearlessly, and launch faster.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>“We are excited to put our technology to the service of one of the sleekest on-chain dex to supercharge its capabilities even more. Flash Trade can shape the next generation of decentralized perpetual exchanges.” - <a href="https://x.com/supermarioblock">Andrea Fortugno</a>, Co-Founder of MagicBlock</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This partnership is more than just a collaboration; it’s a call to developers everywhere: the future of DeFi is ready to be built, and with MagicBlock, the possibilities are boundless.
Together with Flash Trade, we are making what once seemed impossible, inevitable.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="unleash-the-power-of-magicblock">Unleash the Power of MagicBlock</h2>

<p>Get ready to explore new horizons of performance and innovation in decentralized finance.</p>

<p>Explore our <a href="https://docs.magicblock.gg/introduction">documentation</a>, or follow us on <a href="https://x.com/magicblock">Twitter (X)</a> and <a href="https://discord.com/invite/MBkdC3gxcv">Discord</a> to stay in the loop. Let’s build the future—faster, smarter, together.</p>]]></content><author><name>Magicblock</name></author><category term="Announcement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we’re thrilled to announce a transformative partnership with Flash Trade, Solana’s leading asset-backed perpetuals exchange. Together, we’re setting a new standard for DeFi, delivering lightning-fast trading experiences that redefine the boundaries of speed and composability. At MagicBlock, we empower builders to create without compromise—enabling performance that rivals traditional finance while embracing the trustless, decentralized ethos of Web3. By joining forces with Flash Trade, we’re unlocking the potential for a Binance-like exchange built entirely on Solana!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/flashtrade.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/flashtrade.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Sourcing the MagicBlock Ephemeral Validator</title><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/ephemeral-validator/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Sourcing the MagicBlock Ephemeral Validator" /><published>2024-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/ephemeral-validator</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.magicblock.gg/ephemeral-validator/"><![CDATA[<p>Today, we’re excited to announce the open sourcing of the <a href="https://github.com/magicblock-labs/ephemeral-validator">MagicBlock Ephemeral Validator</a>, a non-voting and lightweight SVM-runtime that brings real-time, elastic compute to Solana.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>TLDR: You can now write your entire Web2 server logic on Solana and execute arbitrary account updates on Just-In-Time (JIT) SVM instances, which run in parallel with Solana and replace centralized servers. Ephemeral Validators are designed to to use the SVM as a serverless, elastic compute environment for real-time use cases while keeping all smart contracts and state on Mainnet. Forget traditional servers. Just build on Solana and use MagicBlock to access real-time, elastic compute when you need it.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="why-we-built-it">Why We Built It</h2>

<p>Short version: to bring <strong>real-time</strong>, **elastic compute ** to Solana.</p>

<p>Long version: We believe Solana will become the kernel for global finance. As applications mature and users demand real-time interactions, we see the potential to unlock new experiences that are natively composable with Solana state and run entirely on the SVM instead of a centralized server. While Solana provides exceptional throughput, use cases such as fully onchain games, decentralized social networks or trustless high-frequency financial products require even more scalability. With Ephemeral Rollups, developers can implement the entire logic of these apps on Solana and execute computations that would normally run on a server in a temporary, specialized SVM environment, gaining persistence, composability and verifiability for their applications.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-the-magicblock-ephemeral-validator">What Is the MagicBlock Ephemeral Validator?</h2>

<p>The MagicBlock Ephemeral Validator is a non-voting, lightweight SVM-runtime that clones accounts and programs just-in-time (JIT) and settles state to a reference cluster. An Ephemeral validator can run as close as possible to the users to reduce networking latency and it can be run as a sidecar to the Mainnet Validator Clients, standalone or by users themselves given the <a href="https://x.com/PiccoGabriele/status/1828464238442226032">lowered hardware requirements</a>. Node operators can increase their profitability processing the transactions that would otherwise be implemented in a traditional server or would make little sense to run on Mainnet because they are uneconomical or for latency &amp; runtime limitations.
There are 3 main components that the Ephemeral Validator interface with</p>

<h2 id="the-ephemeral-execution-environment">The Ephemeral execution environment</h2>

<p>Ephemeral validators don’t participate in consensus nor can create new Accounts. Ephemeral Validator can only process state transitions on accounts delegated to the delegation program. Once an account has been delegated onchain, the Ephemeral Node clones the account and all the programs associated with it. The delegated state is natively locked on Solana and can be modified in the Ephemeral environment. Since the consensus is postponed to the commitment stage, the slot time can be arbitrarily short. Transactions are processed on a first-come-first-served (FCFS) basis and intra-slot updates allow users to subscribe to real-time data, minimising end-to-end latency. Ephemeral rollups open a new design space to scale elastically, where ordering and sequencing can be implemented as part of the smart contract logic. Additionally, even the same smart contract can dynamically execute some instruction in the ER (a fast-pace action), while some other on mainnet (e.g. depositing liquidity, doing a swap, minting, dispatching a reward, ..). Lastly, the ability to run dedicated  runtime leaves the design space open for further customization for application specific use-cases (e.g. a free ticking or randomness) that wouldn’t be possible or make sense to run on Mainnet.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/ephemeral_validator_diagram.png" alt="Ephemeral Validator Architecture" /></p>

<hr />

<h2 id="a-supercharged-development-environment">A supercharged development environment</h2>

<p>The Ephemeral Validator has been optimized for execution and it can be used as a supercharged development environment. Check out <a href="https://luzid.app/">luzid.app</a> if you want to develop at blazing speed!</p>

<h2 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h2>

<p>By open-sourcing the validator, we aim to foster collaboration among developers and accelerate adoption of real-time onchain applications.
This release is just the beginning. In the coming months, we plan to:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Introduce further optimizations to enhance the validator’s performance.</li>
  <li>Provide more in-depth documentation and tutorials for developers.</li>
  <li>Launch community initiatives, including hackathons and grants</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="join-the-conversation">Join the Conversation</h2>

<p>We’re thrilled to share this milestone with you and can’t wait to see what the community builds with the MagicBlock Ephemeral Validator. Share your thoughts, feedback, and projects with us on <a href="https://x.com/magicblock">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://discord.com/invite/MBkdC3gxcv">Discord</a>, or <a href="https://github.com/magicblock-labs">GitHub</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Magicblock</name></author><category term="Announcement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we’re excited to announce the open sourcing of the MagicBlock Ephemeral Validator, a non-voting and lightweight SVM-runtime that brings real-time, elastic compute to Solana.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/ephemeral_validator.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/ephemeral_validator.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Zeebit: Transparent and provably fair games of chance</title><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/zeebit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zeebit: Transparent and provably fair games of chance" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/zeebit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.magicblock.gg/zeebit/"><![CDATA[<p>Zeebit is a gaming platform (available at <a href="https://zeebit.io/">Zeebit.io</a> ) focused on delivering a wide range of games of chance. The mantra of Zeebit has always been providing Web2-like user experiences, while being transparent, permissionless, fair and self-custodied. Despite its obsessive focus on users, Zeebit’s growth was hampered significantly earlier this year as a result of Solana’s congestion. Zeebit’s users could hardly land transactions. Even in scenarios where the network was not degraded, users’ interactions can take anywhere between 0.5s to 1.5s – significantly slower than the off-chain products Zeebit is competing with.</p>

<h2 id="challenge-web2-like-ux-with-solana-liquidity">Challenge: Web2-Like UX with Solana Liquidity</h2>

<p>To achieve its goal of delivering a decentralized and provably fair experience, Zeebit needed a solution that could:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Provide a fast, seamless user experience without the typical friction associated with blockchain transactions, like gas fees and transaction delays.</li>
  <li>Maintain composability with Solana liquidity and interact seamlessly with the wider Solana ecosystem.</li>
  <li>Scale to support a growing number of players, ensuring consistent real-time performance even as demand increased.
Traditional L2 approaches lead to liquidity fragmentation and increased user friction, both of which run counter to Zeebit’s objective of a Web2-like experience.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="solution-delegating-into-ephemeral-rollups-for-every-game-interaction">Solution: Delegating into Ephemeral Rollups for Every Game interaction</h2>

<p>To meet these challenges, Zeebit makes use of Ephemeral Rollups to power its games. From a user perspective, Ephemeral Rollups allow Zeebit to built the following flow:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Players allocate funds to a smart contract account on Solana, signalling the intent to play.</li>
  <li>During  game play, some transactions are offloaded to the ephemeral validator for real-time interaction – ensuring that game logic can be processed with minimal latency.</li>
  <li>The experience is seamless and gasless – as Zeebit is acting as fee payer in the ephemeral node, giving players the fluid experience they expect without compromising decentralization.</li>
  <li>When the game ends, a game state gets committed on Solana where the payout happens, preserving liquidity and ensuring player funds remain on the L1.</li>
</ul>

<p>By delegating each game into Ephemeral Rollups, Zeebit was able to achieve web2-like performance while maintaining the composability benefits of Solana.</p>

<h2 id="results-an-immersive-gasless-fully-on-chain-experience">Results: An Immersive, Gasless, Fully On-Chain Experience</h2>

<p>With MagicBlock’s Ephemeral Rollups, Zeebit successfully bridged the gap between Web2 performance and fully on-chain decentralization, achieving:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Web2-like User Experience</strong>: Thanks to Ephemeral Rollups, Zeebit players enjoy a fast, gasless, and uninterrupted gaming experience that feels identical to traditional online games.</li>
  <li><strong>Solana Liquidity and Composability</strong>: Zeebit’s games are on Solana, allowing them to leverage all the existing tokens and smart contracts without fragmentation or bridging.</li>
  <li><strong>Scalability</strong>: The architecture scales seamlessly as the number of concurrent players grows, maintaining real-time interactivity without compromising performance.</li>
  <li><strong>Modularity</strong>: Zeebit can introduce new game features and integrate with additional Solana primitives quickly and efficiently, keeping their gaming experiences fresh and engaging.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>“When congestion first hit, the project really took a major blow. While the situation did improve, it was clear the promise of perpetually and consistently high speed and low cost transaction may no longer be guaranteed on Solana Mainnet. MagicBlock’s Ephemeral Rollup model was a game-changer in enabling Zeebit’s vision. Web3 security and transparency with web2 UX was always Zeebit’s mandate, and MagicBlock is a key enabler of this mission. ”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Bayes, Zeebit founder</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Zeebit built an extremely interesting use case that shows the interplays between Solana and Ephemeral Rollups. In order to launch successful dapps at scale we need the same attention to details and focus that Zeebit has for its product and we are proud to help them achieve this without leaving Solana ” —</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Andrea Fortugno, MagicBlock cofounder &amp; CEO</p>

<h3 id="about-magicblock">About MagicBlock</h3>

<p>MagicBlock is a high-performance engine for fully onchain games and applications. With Ephemeral Rollups, MagicBlock empowers developers to build real-time and composable decentralized applications.</p>]]></content><author><name>Magicblock</name></author><category term="Announcement" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zeebit is a gaming platform (available at Zeebit.io ) focused on delivering a wide range of games of chance. The mantra of Zeebit has always been providing Web2-like user experiences, while being transparent, permissionless, fair and self-custodied. Despite its obsessive focus on users, Zeebit’s growth was hampered significantly earlier this year as a result of Solana’s congestion. Zeebit’s users could hardly land transactions. Even in scenarios where the network was not degraded, users’ interactions can take anywhere between 0.5s to 1.5s – significantly slower than the off-chain products Zeebit is competing with.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/zeebit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/zeebit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Supersize: a next-gen real-time PvP game on Solana</title><link href="https://blog.magicblock.gg/supersize/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Supersize: a next-gen real-time PvP game on Solana" /><published>2024-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.magicblock.gg/supersize</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.magicblock.gg/supersize/"><![CDATA[<p>Supersize is a next-generation gaming platform (available at <a href="http://supersize.gg:3000/">Supersize.gg</a>) pushing the boundaries of fully onchain gaming on Solana with a simple, powerful vision: financial markets meet .io style game. Supersize is developing a real-time multiplayer experience where users compete for resources in a customizable PvP setting. The game is built entirely onchain (state and logic) and blends financial incentives, UGC and the simplicity of agar.io to create truly innovative game dynamics. The challenge? Creating an entirely onchain experience that could run with real-time latency and impeccable UX without composability fragmentation.</p>

<h2 id="challenge-real-time-latency-without-fragmenting-solana-liquidity-and-state">Challenge: real-time latency without fragmenting Solana liquidity and state</h2>

<p>Supersize required a framework that could handle:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Real-time latency for an ever growing number of concurrent players</li>
  <li>Composability with Solana liquidity and smart contracts</li>
  <li>Seamless user experience despite all interactions being onchain transactions</li>
</ul>

<p>Supersize knew that traditional L2 architecture would struggle to meet these needs due to  well-known issues of liquidity fragmentation and the inability to offer consistent real time latency to a globally distributed audience.</p>

<h2 id="solution-leveraging-bolt-ecs--ephemeral-rollups">Solution: Leveraging BOLT ECS + Ephemeral Rollups</h2>

<p>Supersize turned to MagicBlock and leveraged <a href="https://docs.magicblock.gg/Build/Bolt/introduction">BOLT</a> ECS (Entity-Component-System) and Ephemeral Rollups to bring its vision to life. BOLT is an ECS framework built on top of Anchor that enabled Supersize to efficiently structure game logic on Solana, leaving space for the introduction of new systems to extend and modify the game. MagicBlock’s Ephemeral Rollups provided the low-latency performance needed for real-time interactions, while keeping liquidity and all the smart contract on Solana. Additionally, by means of co-location, Ephemeral Rollups further reduce the networking latency (~30ms end-to-end) offering performances on par with traditional multiplayer game servers.</p>

<h2 id="results-a-seamless-fully-on-chain-gaming-experience">Results: A Seamless, Fully On-Chain Gaming Experience</h2>

<p>Using BOLT ECS and Ephemeral Rollups, Supersize was able to deliver a fully onchain game that matched all their criteria with:</p>

<ul>
  <li>High scalability and real-time latency: Supersize can elastically scale to support more players who interact with each others in real-time</li>
  <li>Solana liquidity and composability: the game is built on Solana and can leverage SOL, BONK, LST or any other token without bridging.</li>
  <li>Modularity: Supersize can compose with any smart contract and rapidly introduce new game mechanics or upgrades without having to redeploy the entire game architecture.</li>
  <li>UX: Thanks to Ephemeral Rollups the gameplay is fast and offers players a seamless, gasless and uninterrupted experience.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Coming from EVM, I was ready to make big compromises to build Supersize fully onchain. But, by leveraging Magicblock’s stack to build directly on Solana, not only does Supersize not compromise on UX, but it also synergizes elegantly with the broader Solana ecosystem.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Lewis Arnsten, Supersize founder</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I am extremely excited to see Supersize advancing the narrative of what is possible with FOCG. I am extremely bullish on Solana-first experiences that tap into the liquidity and existing primitives of the chain without sacrificing a seamless user experience”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Andrea Fortugno, MagicBlock cofounder &amp; CEO</p>

<h2 id="about-magicblock">About MagicBlock</h2>
<p>MagicBlock is a high-performance engine for fully onchain games and applications. With Ephemeral Rollups, MagicBlock empowers developers to build real-time and composable decentralized applications.
Learn more at <a href="https://docs.magicblock.gg/">MagicBlock</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Magicblock</name></author><category term="Announcement" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supersize is a next-generation gaming platform (available at Supersize.gg) pushing the boundaries of fully onchain gaming on Solana with a simple, powerful vision: financial markets meet .io style game. Supersize is developing a real-time multiplayer experience where users compete for resources in a customizable PvP setting. The game is built entirely onchain (state and logic) and blends financial incentives, UGC and the simplicity of agar.io to create truly innovative game dynamics. The challenge? Creating an entirely onchain experience that could run with real-time latency and impeccable UX without composability fragmentation.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/supersize.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.magicblock.gg/assets/images/supersize.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>